(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I'm Jon M. Chu. And I'm not a dancer,
أنا جون شو, وأنا لست براقص
I'm not a choreographer -- I'm actually a filmmaker, a storyteller.
أنا لست بمصمم رقصات, أنا في الواقع صانع أفلام, أنا راوي قصص.
I directed a movie two years ago
لقد أخرجت فيلما قبل عامين
called "Step Up 2: The Streets."
اسمه "خطوة الى الشارع"
Anybody? Anybody? Yeah!
هل من أحد؟ هل من أحد؟ نعم
During that movie I got to meet a ton of hip-hop dancers --
خلال هذا الفيلم حصلت على الفرصة للقاء العديد من الراقصين
amazing, the best in the world --
مذهلين, وأفضلهم في العالم
and they brought me into a society, the sort of underground
ونقلوني الى مجتمع, نوعا ما مثل تحت الأرض
street culture that blew my mind.
ثقافة الشارع التي أذهلتني تماما
I mean, this is literally human beings
أعني أن هذا هو فعلا أشخاص بمعنى الكلمة
with super-human strength and abilities.
مع قوة بشرية وقدرات فائقة
They could fly in the air. They could bend their elbow all the way back.
يمكن أن يطيرون في الهواء. بأستطاعتهم لوي كوعهم تماما الى الخلف
They could spin on their heads for 80 times in a row.
يمكنهم أن يدوروا على رؤوسهم 80 مرة على التوالي.
I'd never seen anything like that.
أنا لم أر قط شيئا كهذا.
When I was growing up, my heroes were people like
عندما كنت أكبر, أبطالي كانوا أشخاص مثل
Fred Astaire, Gene Kelly, Michael Jackson.
فريد أستير ، جين كيلي ، ومايكل جاكسون.
I grew up in a musical family.
لقد نشأت في أسرة موسيقية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And those guys, those were like, ultimate heroes.
وهؤلاء الأشخاص, هؤلاء كانوا مثل الأبطال النهائيين
Being a shy, little, skinny Asian kid growing up in the Silicon Valley
كوني اسيوي ضعيف خجول يعيش في السيليكون فالي
with low self-esteem, those guys made me believe in something bigger.
مع احترام منخفض للذات ، هؤلاء الرجال جعلوني اؤمن بشيء أكبر.
Those guys made me want to, like, "I'm going to do that
هؤلاء الاشخاص حسسوني بأني, مثل "سوف أقوم
moonwalk at that bar mitzvah tonight for that girl."
برقصة القمر في بار ميتزفاه الليلة من أجل تلك الفتاة"
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And it seems like those dance heroes have disappeared,
ويبدو أن مثل ابطال الرقص هؤلاء اختفوا ،
sort of relegated to the background of pop stars and music videos.
نوعا ما كخلفية لنجوم البوب والموسيقى والفيديو
But after seeing what I've seen,
ولكن بعد أن رأيت ما رأيت ،
the truth is, they have not disappeared at all.
الحقيقة هي انهم لم يختفوا على الاطلاق
They're here, getting better and better every day.
إنهم موجودون هنا, يصيرون أفضل وأفضل كل يوم
And dance has progressed.
والرقص قد أحرز تقدما
It is insane what dance is right now.
انه جنون ما هو عليه الرقص الان
Dance has never had a better friend than technology.
الرقص لم يكن لديه صديق أفضل من التكنولوجيا.
Online videos and social networking ...
أفلام الفيديو على الانترنت والشبكات الاجتماعية..
dancers have created a whole global laboratory online
الراقصون قد خلقوا مختبرات عالمية على الانترنت
for dance, where kids in Japan are taking moves
للرقص ، حيث الاطفال في اليابان يأخذون خطوات
from a YouTube video created in Detroit,
من فيديو يوتيوب إنشئ في مدينة ديترويت ،
building on it within days and releasing a new video,
يبنون عليه في غضون أيام ويطلقون شريطا جديدا
while teenagers in California are taking the Japanese video and remixing it
في حين أن المراهقين في ولاية كاليفورنيا يأخذون الفيديو الياباني ويعدلون عليه
with a Philly flair to create a whole new dance style in itself.
مع ذوق فيلاديلفي لخلق نمط جديد كليا للرقص في حد ذاته.
And this is happening every day.
وهذا يحدث كل يوم.
And from these bedrooms and living rooms and garages,
وهذه من غرف النوم والمعيشة والمرائب ،
with cheap webcams,
مع كاميرات انترنت رخيصة ،
lies the world's great dancers of tomorrow.
يكمن راقصوا الغد العالميين
Our Fred Astaires, our Gene Kellys
فريد استيريس الخاص بنا, وجين كلي التابعة لنا
our Michael Jacksons are right at our fingertips,
مايكل جاكسون التابع لنا موجود عند أطراف أصابعنا
and may not have that opportunity, except for us.
وربما لا تكون لديه الفرصة ، ما عدا معنا.
So, we created the LXD,
لذلك أنشأنا: the LXD,
sort of a -- the Legion of Extraordinary Dancers,
نوعا ما, فيلق الراقصون الغير عاديوون
a justice league of dancers that believe
عصبة عادلة من الراقصين الذين يؤمنون
that dance can have a transformative effect on the world.
ان الرقص يمكن ان يكون لها تأثير تحولي على العالم.
A living, breathing comic book series,
سلسلة كتاب هزلي حية تتنفس
but unlike Spiderman and Iron Man,
ولكن على عكس الرجل العنكبوت والرجل الحديدي ،
these guys can actually do it.
هؤلاء الرجال في الواقع يقومون به
And we're going to show you some today. So, let me introduce to you,
وسوف نريكم بعضا منه اليوم. فاسمحوا لي بأن اقدم لكم
some of our heroes right now.
بعض من الابطال الآن.
We got Madd Chadd,
لدينا ماد تشاد
Lil' C, Kid David and J Smooth.
ليل سي, كيد دايفيد, وجي سموث
Please be excited, have fun, yell, scream.
ارجوكم تحمسوا, استمتعوا, نادوا واصرخوا
Ladies and gentlemen: The LXD.
سيداتي وسادتيThe LXD.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
(Video): Madd Chadd: When people first see me,
(فيديو) ماد شاد: عندما يراني الناس
I get a lot of different reactions actually.
أحصل على الكثير من ردود الفعل المختلفة في الواقع.
Sometimes you would think that maybe kids would enjoy it,
احيانا قد تفكر انه ربما يكون الاطفال من شأنهم أن يتمتعوا بهذا
but sometimes they get a little freaked out.
ولكن في بعض الأحيان يخافون قليلا
And, I don't know, I kind of get a kick out of that a little bit.
ولا أعرف, ولكن أتحمس لذلك قليلا نوعا ما
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
J Smooth: When I'm in the zone -- I'm dancing and free styling it --
جي سموث: عندما أكون في المنطقة, ارقص وأقوم بالتصميم الحر له
I actually visually kind of picture
أنا نوعا ما أتخيل بصريا
lines, and moving them.
خطوط وأقوم بتحريكها
I think of like, Transformers,
أفكر مثل: المتحولون
like how panels open and then they fold,
مثل كيف تفتح الألواح ومن ثم تطوى
they fold in, and then you close that panel.
يطوون, ومن ثم تغلق تلك الألواح
And then another thing opens,
وبعدها يفتح شئ اخر
you close that.
تغلق ذلك
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Kid David: It's kind of like, honestly a lot of times
كيد دايفيد: انه نوعا ما مثل, في الحقيقة الكثير من الأوقات
I don't really know what's going on
لا أعرف تماما ما يحدث
when I'm dancing.
عندما أكون أرقص
Because at that point it's just really like, it's my body and the music.
لأنه في تلك اللحظة, إنه فعلا مثل انه جسمي والموسيقى
It's not really a conscious decision,
انه ليس حقا قرارا واعيا ،
"I'm going to do this next, I'm going to do this."
"سوف أقوم بهذا الان, وهذا بعد منه"
It's kind of like this other level
انه نوعا ما مثل المرحلة الاخرى
where you can't make choices anymore,
عندما لا تمتلك الخيارات بعد الان
and it's just your body reacting to certain sounds in the music.
وإنه مجرد جسمك يتفاعل لأصوات معينة في الموسيقى
I got my name just because I was so young.
حصلت على اسمي لأني كنت صغيرا جدا
I was young when I started. I was younger than a lot of the people I was dancing with.
كنت صغيرا جدا عندما بدأت. كنت أصغر من الكثير من الصغار الذين كنت أرقص معهم
So, it was always like, they called me Kid David, because I was the kid.
لذلك, كانوا دائما ينادوني كيد دايفيد - دايفيد الصغير - , لأني كنت صغيرا
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
L'il C: I tell them to create a ball,
ليل سي: أقول لهم بأن يشكلوا كرة
and then you just use that ball of energy.
ومن ثم فقط استعمل تلك الكرة من الطاقة
And instead of throwing it out, people would think
وبدلا من رميها في الخارج, يعتقد الناس
that's a krump move, that's a krump move.
بأنها حركة الكرامب, هذه حركة كرامب
That's not a krump move. You're going to throw it out,
تلك ليست حركة كرامب. سوف تقوم برميها في الخارج
you throw it out, and you hold it.
ترميها وتمسكها
And you let it go, and then right when you see the tail,
وتتركها, وبعدها عندما ترى الذيل
you grab it by the tail, then you bring it back in.
تمسك به من ذيله, وتحضره للداخل
And you just got this piece of energy
وتستغنى عن هذه القطعة من الطاقة
and you just, you're manipulating it.
وأنت فقط, تتلاعب بها
You know, you create power, then you tame it.
أتعلم, أنت تخلق القوة, ومن ثم تدربها
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)